<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2025 Jedielson da Fonseca -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.github.jedifonseca.mass_renamer</id>
  
  <name>Mass Renamer</name>
  <summary>Rename multiple files at once quickly and easily</summary>
  
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>Apache-2.0</project_license>
  
  <developer id="com.github.jedifonseca">
    <name>Jedielson da Fonseca</name>
  </developer>
  
  <description>
    <p>
      Mass Renamer is a simple yet powerful tool for renaming multiple files simultaneously. It is ideal for organizing photo collections, music libraries, or any set of files that need a consistent naming pattern.
    </p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Numbered list view of original and new names.</li>
      <li>Automatically load all filenames from a selected folder, if so desired.</li>
      <li>Quickly add or remove any file extensions.</li>
      <li>Transfer extensions from original names to new names.</li>
      <li>Undo the last renaming operation safely, even after an app or system crash.</li>
      <li>Cross-platform filename validation for Windows, macOS, Linux and Android.</li>
      <li>Multiple themes to match your desktop environment.</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  
  <launchable type="desktop-id">massrenamer.desktop</launchable>
  
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Main window with Mint-Y-Dark-Aqua theme</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/JediFonseca/mass_renamer/main/screenshots/img01.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Settings window with Ubuntu light theme</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/JediFonseca/mass_renamer/main/screenshots/img02.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <releases>
    <release version="2.2" date="2025-09-12">
      <description>
        <p>This is a major update focused on adding a comprehensive settings menu, improving user feedback during operations, and increasing safety and stability.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>New Settings Window: Includes cross-platform filename validation and customizable extensions.</li>
          <li>Operation Progress Counter: A percentage counter is now displayed during "Rename" and "Undo" tasks.</li>
          <li>Automatic Log Saving: Logs for "Rename" and "Undo" are now saved in the config folder.</li>
          <li>Enhanced Undo Safety: The undo feature now checks for file modifications before running, preventing data loss.</li>
          <li>Improved Conflict Detection: Now detects duplicate names within the new names list itself.</li>
          <li>New Themes: Added Adwaita and Breeze themes, with updated color palettes.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/JediFonseca/mass_renamer</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/JediFonseca/mass_renamer/issues</url>
  
</component>
